Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about eating food and certain foods that people
我是Catherine，今天我们要聊聊吃东西，以及一些人们不吃的食物。
don't eat.
不吃的食物。
That's right.
没错。
So today we have special diets.
所以今天我们讲的是特殊饮食。
We're going to talk all about being a vegetarian or a vegan and we're going to explain all
我们要全面聊聊成为素食者或纯素食者，等我们回来时会解释所有这些词。
these words when we come back.
这些词。
So now let's just listen to the dialogue.
那么现在我们先来听对话。
Hey, Julie.
嘿，Julie。
Do you want to go grab something to eat?
你想去吃点东西吗？
Sure.
好啊。
What do you feel like having?
你想吃什么？
I really feel like having a big juicy steak.
我真想来一大块多汁的牛排。
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
I don't eat meat, but that's fine.
我不吃肉，不过没关系。
I'm sure wherever we're going, they will have other options, right?
我相信不管我们去哪儿，他们都会有别的选择，对吧？
I didn't know you were a vegetarian.
我不知道你是个素食者。
I'm not.
我不是。
I'm a vegan.
我是纯素食者。
A what?
什么？
A vegan.
纯素食者。
I don't eat or use any animal-based products.
我不吃也不使用任何动物制品。
I don't wear leather, eat eggs, drink milk or anything that comes from an animal.
我不穿皮革，不吃鸡蛋，不喝牛奶，也不吃任何来自动物的东西。
I used to be a pescatarian before, which basically means you don't eat meat, but still have fish
我以前是个鱼素者，基本上就是不吃肉，但吃鱼。
and seafood.
和海鲜。
Wow.
哇。
That's interesting.
真有意思。
It must be tough.
那一定很难吧。
It's a bit difficult to find vegetarian-friendly restaurants sometimes, but since more and
有时候确实很难找到适合素食者的餐厅，但如今越来越多的人成为素食者或纯素食者，所以情况没那么难了。
more people are vegetarians or vegans nowadays, it's getting a bit less difficult.
越来越容易了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now probably a lot of you have an idea of what it means to be a vegetarian, but let's
现在可能很多人对素食者是什么意思有概念，但让我们在“语言小贴士”环节仔细看看这个词以及更多词汇。
take a look at that word and many more on Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Language Takeaway.
So a vegetarian is a noun.
所以素食者是一个名词。
I am a vegetarian.
我是一个素食者。
Yeah.
是的。
Vegetarian is a noun.
素食者是名词。
It's a person.
它指一个人。
You say I am a vegetarian.
你说“我是一个素食者”。
He is a vegetarian.
“他是一个素食者”。
And in this case, a vegetarian person does not eat meat.
在这种情况下，素食者不吃肉。
So no chicken, no beef, none of that stuff.
所以没有鸡肉、牛肉，那些东西都不吃。
That's right.
没错。
So as you can see, it has the prefix veget, like vegetable.
所以你看，它有前缀“veget”，就像“vegetable”（蔬菜）。
So that's what they eat.
所以他们吃蔬菜。
They just eat vegetables.
他们只吃蔬菜。
And it's a little bit hard to say what all vegetarians do or don't eat because some people
要准确说出所有素食者吃或不吃什么有点难，因为有些人有不同的规矩。
have different rules.
没错。
That's right.
Some people eat eggs, some people don't.
有些人吃鸡蛋，有些人不吃。
But there is something that is a little bit different from a vegetarian.
但有一种和素食者有点不同的。
It's called a vegan and this person has many, many rules about what he can or cannot eat.
它叫纯素食者，这种人对自己能吃什么或不能吃什么有很多很多规矩。
Right.
对。
So a vegetarian basically does not eat meat.
所以素食者基本上不吃肉。
A vegan, as we saw in our dialogue, doesn't wear leather, for example, doesn't wear leather
纯素食者，就像我们在对话中看到的，不穿皮革，比如不穿皮鞋或皮夹克，也不使用或吃任何来自动物的东西。
shoes or a jacket or use or eat anything that comes from an animal.
没错。
That's right.
No eggs, right?
不吃鸡蛋，对吧？
No foods that might have any animal products in them.
不吃任何可能含有动物制品的食物。
So vegans often try to find foods at the grocery store that come from natural products that
所以纯素食者经常在杂货店找那些来自天然、非动物来源的产品。
are not animal based.
不是动物来源的。
And so there has to be a symbol on the back of the box or the jar that says that it's
所以盒子或罐子背面必须有一个标志，表明它是纯素食的。
vegan.
纯素食的。
That's right.
没错。
So in that case, they don't drink milk, they don't eat eggs, nothing that you can think
所以在这种情况下，他们不喝牛奶，不吃鸡蛋，任何你能想到的来自动物的东西都不吃。
of that comes from an animal.
来自动物的东西。
But on the other hand, this person used to be a pescatarian.
但另一方面，这个人以前是个鱼素者。
So this is another type of person that has a special diet, very much like a vegetarian.
所以这是另一种有特殊饮食的人，和素食者很像。
A pescatarian is a person who is a vegetarian but who also eats fish.
鱼素者是一个素食者，但也吃鱼。
And so maybe I'm a pescatarian because I don't consider fish to be animals.
所以也许我是个鱼素者，因为我不把鱼看作动物。
Okay.
好的。
So I don't eat lamb, I don't eat chicken, but I do eat fish.
所以我不吃羊肉，不吃鸡肉，但我吃鱼。
I'm a pescatarian.
我是个鱼素者。
All right.
好的。
So a vegetarian does not eat fish or any type of meat, the same as a vegan, but a pescatarian
所以素食者不吃鱼或任何肉类，和纯素食者一样，但鱼素者会吃虾、鱼以及任何来自海洋的动物。
does eat maybe shrimp and fish and any type of animal from the sea.
来自海洋的动物。
Okay.
好的。
And well, that brings us up to our next word.
嗯，这就引出了我们的下一个词。
A pescatarian will eat seafood.
鱼素者会吃海鲜。
Seafood is a word we use to describe animals that come from the sea.
海鲜这个词用来描述来自海洋的动物。
So not just fish.
所以不仅仅是鱼。
So like you said, shrimp and lobster.
就像你说的，虾和龙虾。
You could even think of really delicious food like a seafood pasta or a seafood salad, octopus,
你甚至可以想到非常美味的食物，比如海鲜意面或海鲜沙拉、章鱼，
things like that.
诸如此类的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So you got clams, you have oysters, anything that comes from the sea is considered seafood.
所以有蛤蜊、牡蛎，任何来自海洋的东西都被视为海鲜。
Right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And our last word in language takeaway is an adjective.
我们语言摘录中的最后一个词是一个形容词。
We heard at the end of the dialogue, our character said, it must be tough.
我们在对话结尾听到，角色说：那一定很艰难。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
That's an interesting word because in English it has a few different meanings, but what
这个词很有趣，因为在英语中有几种不同的意思，但
was the meaning of the word tough in today's dialogue?
在今天的对话中，tough 这个词是什么意思？
In today's dialogue, when the person said it must be tough, it's basically saying it
在今天的对话中，当有人说“那一定很艰难”时，基本上是在说
must be difficult.
那一定很困难。
It must be difficult to be a vegetarian.
当素食主义者一定很困难。
Right.
对。
So it's a hard situation.
所以这是一个艰难的情况。
You could also say, oh man, this homework is really tough.
你也可以说：哦，天哪，这作业真难。
That means it's hard.
意思是很难。
It's difficult.
很困难。
All right.
好的。
Great.
很好。
So we've taken a look at a lot of key words there.
我们已经看了很多关键词。
Why don't we take a break?
我们休息一下怎么样？
Listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
再听一遍我们的对话，我们一会儿回来。
Hey Julie, do you want to go grab something to eat?
嘿，朱莉，你想去随便吃点东西吗？
Sure.
当然。
What do you feel like having?
你想吃什么？
I really feel like having a big juicy steak.
我真想吃一大块多汁的牛排。
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
I don't eat meat, but that's fine.
我不吃肉，但没关系。
I'm sure wherever we're going, they will have other options.
我相信不管我们去哪里，他们都会有其他选择。
Right?
对吧？
I didn't know you were a vegetarian.
我不知道你是素食主义者。
I'm not.
我不是。
I'm a vegan.
我是纯素食者。
A what?
什么？
A vegan.
纯素食者。
I don't eat or use any animal-based products.
我不吃也不使用任何动物制品。
I don't wear leather, eat eggs, drink milk, or anything that comes from an animal.
我不穿皮革，不吃鸡蛋，不喝牛奶，也不吃任何来自动物的东西。
I used to be a pescatarian before, which basically means you don't eat meat, but still have fish
我以前是鱼素者，基本上就是不吃肉，但吃鱼
and seafood.
和海鲜。
Wow.
哇。
That's interesting.
真有意思。
It must be tough.
那一定很艰难。
It's a bit difficult to find vegetarian-friendly restaurants sometimes, but since more and
有时候找适合素食者的餐厅有点困难，但因为现在
more people are vegetarians or vegans nowadays, it's getting a bit less difficult.
越来越多的人是素食者或纯素食者，所以变得没那么难了。
All right.
好的。
Now we've prepared three phrases for you.
现在我们为你准备了三个短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
让我们在流利度提升环节看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
So there's a very interesting and very, very common phrase at the beginning of today's
今天的对话开头有一个非常有趣且非常常见的短语，我们在英语中经常使用。
dialogue that we use all the time in English.
This is to grab something to eat.
就是“去随便吃点东西”。
The character says, hey Julie, you want to go grab something to eat?
角色说：嘿，朱莉，你想去随便吃点东西吗？
So taking that as a phrase, we are inviting someone to go eat something.
所以作为一个短语，我们在邀请某人去吃点东西。
That's right.
没错。
So I could say, hey, do you want to go eat something?
所以我可以问：嘿，你想去吃点东西吗？
Or I could say, hey, do you want to go grab something to eat?
或者我可以问：嘿，你想去随便吃点东西吗？
Okay.
好的。
And the verb grab is to take or to hold in your hand.
动词 grab 意思是拿或用手抓住。
So you want to go grab something to eat is basically that.
所以“你想去随便吃点东西”基本上就是这个意思。
Right.
对。
But don't be confused because grabbing normally means holding with your hand, but to grab
但别搞混了，因为 grab 通常意味着用手抓住，但“去随便吃点东西”
something to eat generally just means, hey, would you like to go eat something with me?
通常只是说：嘿，你愿意和我一起去吃点东西吗？
Okay.
好的。
And of course we want to go grab something to eat and the guy says, I really feel like
当然，我们想去随便吃点东西，而那个人说：我真想吃
having a big juicy steak.
一大块多汁的牛排。
So we feel like having a steak.
所以我们想吃牛排。
This is very spoken English.
这是很口语化的英语。
So remember when you're talking to your friends, this is okay, but maybe if you're writing
所以记住，和朋友聊天时这样用没问题，但如果你在写
something it's not as good.
东西，可能就不太合适了。
But I feel like a steak means I want to eat a steak.
但“我想吃牛排”意思是我想吃牛排。
Right.
对。
So you're saying you are a steak.
所以你说你是一块牛排。
No, I don't feel like a steak, like a piece of meat, but I do want to eat a piece of,
不，我不觉得自己像牛排，像一块肉，但我确实想吃一块，
I do want to eat a steak.
我确实想吃牛排。
And so I feel like having, or I feel like a steak.
所以我想吃，或者说我想来份牛排。
These are both acceptable in spoken English.
这两种说法在英语口语中都可以接受。
So you basically feel like doing something or you feel like eating something.
所以基本上，你想做某事，或者你想吃某样东西。
For example, if we're going to have dinner, you can say, I feel like having Italian food.
比如，如果我们去吃晚餐，你可以说，我想吃意大利菜。
Yeah.
是的。
I don't feel like having Italian food tonight.
我今晚不想吃意大利菜。
I feel like having Mexican food.
我想吃墨西哥菜。
And I also feel like watching a movie.
我还想看电影。
Exactly.
没错。
So great ways of using feel like, and then a verb like having or watching a movie.
所以“feel like”后面跟动词，比如“having”或“watching a movie”，是很好的用法。
Now getting back to the vegetarian, the vegan aspect of our dialogue, we saw that the girl
现在回到我们对话中关于素食和纯素的部分，我们看到那个女孩
explained how she doesn't eat or use any animal based products.
解释了她如何不吃或不用任何动物制品。
So these three words, animal based products.
所以这三个词是“animal based products”。
So product is basically anything that will be sold or bought.
“product”基本上是指任何会被买卖的东西。
Animal based is a way to describe a product.
“animal based”是用来描述产品的一种方式。
So some products have animal products in them.
所以有些产品含有动物成分。
So for example, my shoes are an animal based product because they are leather and leather
比如，我的鞋子是动物制品，因为它们是皮革做的，而皮革
comes from cows, which are animals.
来自牛，牛是动物。
So you're basically saying that they have something from an animal.
所以你基本上是在说它们含有来自动物的东西。
They are made up of something that comes from an animal like leather shoes.
它们是由动物身上的东西制成的，比如皮鞋。
Exactly.
没错。
And it's not just shoes.
而且不仅仅是鞋子。
It's also shampoo or some of the foods that you eat like in jars and cans.
还有洗发水，或者你吃的一些食物，比如装在罐子或罐头里的。
It's important if you're a vegan to look on the side of the can or the side of the box
如果你是素食主义者，重要的是要看看罐子或盒子的侧面，
and see is this an animal based product?
看看这是不是动物性产品？
Are there animal products in this?
这里面有动物成分吗？
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
A lot of interesting things in this dialogue today.
今天的对话里有很多有趣的内容。
Why don't we listen to it one last time and we'll be back.
我们最后再听一遍，然后回来。
Hey, Julie.
嘿，朱莉。
Do you want to go grab something to eat?
你想去吃点东西吗？
Sure.
当然。
What do you feel like having?
你想吃什么？
I really feel like having a big juicy steak.
我真想来一大块多汁的牛排。
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
I don't eat meat, but that's fine.
我不吃肉，但没关系。
I'm sure wherever we're going, they will have other options, right?
我相信不管我们去哪儿，他们都会有其他选择，对吧？
I didn't know you were a vegetarian.
我不知道你是个素食主义者。
I'm not.
我不是。
I'm a vegan.
我是素食主义者。
A what?
一个什么？
A vegan.
一个素食主义者。
I don't eat or use any animal based products.
我不吃也不使用任何动物制品。
I don't wear leather, eat eggs, drink milk or anything that comes from an animal.
我不穿皮革，不吃鸡蛋，不喝牛奶，也不碰任何动物制品。
I used to be a pescatarian before, which basically means you don't eat meat, but still have fish
我以前是个鱼素者，基本上就是不吃肉，但还吃鱼。
and seafood.
还有海鲜。
Wow.
哇。
That's interesting.
真有意思。
It must be tough.
一定很不容易。
It's a bit difficult to find vegetarian friendly restaurants sometimes, but since more and
有时候找一家适合素食者的餐厅有点难，不过随着越来越多
more people are vegetarians or vegans nowadays, it's getting a bit less difficult.
现在越来越多的人成为素食者或纯素食者，所以情况变得没那么困难了。
All right, so talking about vegan vegetarians, pescatarians, it seems like these diets or
好的，说到纯素食者、素食者、鱼素者，这些饮食方式似乎……
these lifestyles are more and more popular, but as we saw in the dialogue, it can be a
这些生活方式越来越流行，但正如我们在对话中看到的，这可能是一个
little bit difficult, especially maybe in countries where it's not so popular to have
有点难，尤其是在那些不太流行的地方。
these diets.
这些节食法。
Definitely.
当然。
I think that in places where you can find vegan and vegetarian products very easily,
我认为在那些很容易找到纯素和素食产品的地方，
being a vegetarian becomes much more easy because you have more options.
成为素食主义者变得容易多了，因为你有更多选择。
But if you're living in a country where it's very hard to eat a meal without having meat,
但如果你住在一个很难吃到不含肉的饭菜的国家，
then you might just eat potatoes every day and that will get very, very difficult and
那么你可能每天都只吃土豆，这会变得非常非常困难。
very boring.
很无聊。
Well, that's one of the main arguments or the main concerns with people is that even
嗯，这是人们争论或担心的主要问题之一，那就是即使
though you can argue that you can get all the vitamins or many of the vitamins and minerals
尽管你可以争辩说，你可以从食物中获取所有维生素，或者说许多维生素和矿物质。
from nuts and from vegetables, it's still not healthy to completely exclude from your
从坚果和蔬菜中获取的油，完全排除它们仍然不健康。
diet maybe sources of proteins like meat or eggs or dairy products.
饮食可能包括蛋白质来源，比如肉类、鸡蛋或乳制品。
That's right.
没错。
And so in America, for example, it's very easy to find supplements.
比如在美国，就很容易买到营养补充品。
You can take vitamins like calcium and you can have pills that will give you some protein
你可以服用像钙这样的维生素，也可以吃一些能补充蛋白质的药片。
and you can find all sorts of exotic vegetables that will help you supplement your diet.
而且你能找到各种异国蔬菜，帮你补充日常饮食。
But in a place like China, for example, I think it can be a lot harder to find those
但在像中国这样的地方，我觉得要找到那些东西会难得多。
products and to find those supplements.
产品，并找到那些补充剂。
And so being a vegan especially or a vegetarian poses a lot more challenges.
所以，做一个严格的素食主义者或者素食者，会面临更多的挑战。
Especially I think with what you mentioned that products are usually labeled where they
特别是，我觉得就像你提到的，产品通常会在标签上标明产地。
tell you if they have any animal based products in there.
告诉你里面是否含有动物成分。
Whereas in other countries, it's probably not labeled and it's a little bit, even things
而在其他国家，可能就没有标注，甚至有些东西
like getting the fat free things are a little bit more difficult in other countries like
比如在其他国家，想买到脱脂食品会稍微难一些。
for example, China.
例如，中国。
That's right.
没错。
So we would like to know, are there many vegans or vegetarians in your country?
所以我们想知道，你们国家有很多纯素食者或素食者吗？
And if there are, do you think it's hard for them to buy food?
如果有的话，你觉得他们买食物困难吗？
Why or why not?
为什么是或为什么不是？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Take care.
保重。